# Ruben Alfredo Sanchez

Address: 301 Heller Drive, Santa Cruz, CA 95064

Email: ruasanch@ucsc.edu Tel: 702-527-2465

rubenasanchez1.wix.com/personal Web:

QR Code: personal web site



#### **Professional Info**

My knowledgebase stems from a diagnostic laboratory background which branched out to clinical and comparative medicine research. My research interests are in signal cell transduction, working memory, and language acquisition including an extreme fondness for phonetic analysis.

## Education

Bachelor of Science Cognitive Science University of California, Santa Cruz

**June 2015** 

Associate of Science Physics

San Diego Mesa College, San Diego

**June 2011** 

& Bachelor of Arts Linguistics

& Associate of Science Mathematics

Cognitive Science Department

**Linguistics Department** 

#### Honors

Dean's Scholarship UCSC

#### **Academic Research**

Research Assistant

University of California, Santa Cruz

2013 to 2014

Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with After Effects for various

linguistic studies.

Research Assistant

University of California, Davis

Summer 2012

Center for Mind & Brain

Through a summer internship administered Stanford Binet Intelligence Tests, recruited families, coded data, and assisted with fMRI preparations.

Researcher

University of California, Santa Cruz

Spring 2012

Under an independent study mentorship developed, implemented, and

completed a controlled phonological study.

# **Laboratory Skills**

Cell Differentiation Cell Sub-Culture Specimen Processing

NMR PCR

Gel Electrophoresis

# **Programming & Software**

Operating System:

Android iOS Linux

MacOS Windows

# Productivity:

Access Excel OneNote PowerPoint Word

#### Research Based:

Chimera ColWiz ePrime Mendeley Praat PyMol Qiqqa

# Web Design & Animation:

After Effects Blender Flash Illustrator

# **Teaching Experience**

Tutor / Mentor

Foothill College, Los Altos Hills

Pass The Torch Program

2011

Tutored and developed long term collaborations with students while coaching them on productive study habits and critical writing techniques.

**Tutor** 

Foothill College, Los Altos Hills

Volunteer

2011

When the English department closed the writing lab due to budget cuts, I collaborated with the English as a Second Language Club in order to provide free tutoring services to ESL students. I functioned as the first tutor and helped implement the ESL Club writing assistance outreach program.

Tutor

Independent

2010 to 2011

Provided tutoring services to students and adults on academic subjects such as English, French, Algebra, and Calculus.

# **Professional Experience**

Technical Assistant

Pfizer La Jolla, CA Global Research & Development

Jan 2008 to Jun 2009

Performed health observations on a variety of species within the Comparative Medicine Department. Managed and updated the department website.

#### Animal Technician

The Scripps Research Institute La Jolla, CA Immunology

Feb 2007 to Aug 2007

Examined and monitored health concerns. Learned malocclusion treatments, orbital bleeds, peritoneal injections, intra-cardiac punctures, and tumor measurements.

# Leadership Roles

Speaker Series Coordinator	Undergraduate Research Science Association	UCSC	2014
Student Guest Speaker	OLA Commencement Celebration	Foothill College	2011
Organization Board of Directors Rep.	ESL Club & LHM Club	Foothill College	2011
President	Spanish Languages & Spanish Cultures Club	Foothill College	2011
Community Liaison	Latino Heritage Month Committee	Foothill College	2011
Member	International Night Organization Committee	Foothill College	2011
Member	Vietnamese Culture Committee	Foothill College	2011

#### **Professional Affiliations**

Cognitive Science Society Linguistic Society of America Unione Matematica Italiana Real Academia de Ciencias

### Certifications

C.P.R.

For the professional rescuer American Red Cross

fMRI Safety

Dynamic Memory Lab University of California, Davis

## **Natural Languages**

English Italian Spanish French

# **Programming Languages**

HTML 5 CSS 3 JavaScript Python R LaTeX